<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cartography on Hannah Ker</title>
    <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cartography on Hannah Ker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:21:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hannahker.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring approaches for visualizing animal movement on the web</title>
      <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/eagles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/eagles/</guid>
      <description>Movebank is an incredible repository of animal GPS tracks from all over the world, containing data from over 7,000 different studies. A dataset of GPS tracks will include a set of timestamped coordinates that are associated with a given animal. The theory here is that we can connect temporally adjacent coordinates from an animal to create an estimate of its trajectory of movement over time. After discovering this data, I worked on a couple of projects where I explored web-based options for interactive, cartographic visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shaded relief in Blender and R</title>
      <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/blender/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve stepped up from my previous work with rayshader, instead using Blender to create a similarly-styled elevation map. This work is drawn heavily from the amazing tutorial from Daniel Huffman, as well as the Blender tutorial materials from David Garcia. Aside from some styling at the end, I followed this material pretty closely, so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother replicating the walkthrough.
I used elevation data from GEBCO, which has a very handy tool for selecting data for a given area using a bounding box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A minimal map of Vancouver&#39;s street trees</title>
      <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/trees-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/trees-map/</guid>
      <description>I have been a long-time admirer of the &amp;lsquo;Minimal Maps&amp;rsquo; series from Michael Pecirno, and wanted to try to recreate something similar. I really liked his focus on the natural environment and spent a while exploring potential datasets, at a variety of scales. I eventually settled on this dataset of street trees in Vancouver. This dataset has one point for every public tree on Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s boulevards (there are over 140,000!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road network visualizations with OSMnx</title>
      <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/osmnx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/osmnx/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s so satisfying to make some nice looking maps. This time I returned to the more familiar Python and played around with the fabulous OSMnx package from Geoff Boeing. OSMnx is a package for accessing, processing, analyzing, and visualizing road network and building footprint data from OpenStreetMap. This package is very well-documented with many examples, so it was simple enough to get started.
The code that I used to create these maps was pretty much taken directly from this example on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive map of murals in Montreal</title>
      <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/html-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/html-post/</guid>
      <description>See the full map here!
As it turns out, mapping in R is (almost) totally easy!
Some months ago, I found a dataset of all of the locations of Montreal&amp;rsquo;s publicly commissioned murals on the city&amp;rsquo;s open data portal. As someone who has very much enjoyed many of these murals, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to creating an interactive web map with this data for quite a while. My recent foray into the world of spatial analysis in R (thanks to my GIS module this semester) showed me a simple way to create a basic, but quite nice looking, web map using the Leaflet library for R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Lynch and my image of London</title>
      <link>https://hannahker.com/posts/image-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/image-post/</guid>
      <description>Given that I can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of Kevin Lynch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Image of the City&amp;rdquo;, I thought that I would start off my time in London by drawing my own mental map of the city. This map is based on my experiences after being in London for less than a week (so cut me some slack).
Unsurprisingly, my residence at Goodenough College features most prominently in my mental map of London. The Charles Dickens Museum, just down the street, has served as a handy landmark assuring me that I am on the right track when on my way home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
