<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hannah Ker</title><link>https://hannahker.com/</link><description>Recent content on Hannah Ker</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 12:41:46 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hannahker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring approaches for visualizing animal movement on the web</title><link>https://hannahker.com/posts/eagles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/eagles/</guid><description>Movebank is an incredible repository of animal GPS tracks from all over the world, containing data from over 7,000 different studies. A dataset of GPS tracks will include a set of timestamped coordinates that are associated with a given animal. The theory here is that we can connect temporally adjacent coordinates from an animal to create an estimate of its trajectory of movement over time. After discovering this data, I worked on a couple of projects where I explored web-based options for interactive, cartographic visualization.</description></item><item><title>Shaded relief in Blender and R</title><link>https://hannahker.com/posts/blender/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/blender/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve stepped up from my previous work with rayshader, instead using Blender to create a similarly-styled elevation map. This work is drawn heavily from the amazing tutorial from Daniel Huffman, as well as the Blender tutorial materials from David Garcia. Aside from some styling at the end, I followed this material pretty closely, so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother replicating the walkthrough.
I used elevation data from GEBCO, which has a very handy tool for selecting data for a given area using a bounding box.</description></item><item><title>A minimal map of Vancouver's street trees</title><link>https://hannahker.com/posts/trees-map/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/trees-map/</guid><description>I have been a long-time admirer of the &amp;lsquo;Minimal Maps&amp;rsquo; series from Michael Pecirno, and wanted to try to recreate something similar. I really liked his focus on the natural environment and spent a while exploring potential datasets, at a variety of scales. I eventually settled on this dataset of street trees in Vancouver. This dataset has one point for every public tree on Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s boulevards (there are over 140,000!</description></item><item><title>Road network visualizations with OSMnx</title><link>https://hannahker.com/posts/osmnx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/osmnx/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s so satisfying to make some nice looking maps. This time I returned to the more familiar Python and played around with the fabulous OSMnx package from Geoff Boeing. OSMnx is a package for accessing, processing, analyzing, and visualizing road network and building footprint data from OpenStreetMap. This package is very well-documented with many examples, so it was simple enough to get started.
The code that I used to create these maps was pretty much taken directly from this example on Github.</description></item><item><title>Interactive map of murals in Montreal</title><link>https://hannahker.com/posts/html-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/html-post/</guid><description>See the full map here!
As it turns out, mapping in R is (almost) totally easy!
Some months ago, I found a dataset of all of the locations of Montreal&amp;rsquo;s publicly commissioned murals on the city&amp;rsquo;s open data portal. As someone who has very much enjoyed many of these murals, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to creating an interactive web map with this data for quite a while. My recent foray into the world of spatial analysis in R (thanks to my GIS module this semester) showed me a simple way to create a basic, but quite nice looking, web map using the Leaflet library for R.</description></item><item><title>Kevin Lynch and my image of London</title><link>https://hannahker.com/posts/image-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/posts/image-post/</guid><description>Given that I can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of Kevin Lynch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Image of the City&amp;rdquo;, I thought that I would start off my time in London by drawing my own mental map of the city. This map is based on my experiences after being in London for less than a week (so cut me some slack).
Unsurprisingly, my residence at Goodenough College features most prominently in my mental map of London. The Charles Dickens Museum, just down the street, has served as a handy landmark assuring me that I am on the right track when on my way home.</description></item><item><title>Using SVR to predict travel times in London</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/traffic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/traffic/</guid><description>Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ Using data collected from London&amp;rsquo;s ANPR camera system, I built and trained a machine learning model to predict travel times across 22 road links in central London.
The data&amp;nbsp;¶ This data was collected as part of the London Congestion Analysis Project and provides travel times (in sec/meter), aggregated at 5 min intervals for road links throughout London. This data was collected between January 1st, 2011 and January 30th, 2011 and includes observations between 6am-9pm for each day.</description></item><item><title>Using NLP to analyze OpenStreetMap changeset discussions</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/discussions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/discussions/</guid><description>Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ I used topic modelling and sentiment analysis to computationally investigate OpenStreetMap (OSM) changeset discussions. Specifically, I explored the following research question: What is the subject and tone of OSM changeset discussions between contributors in the United States over the past 90 days?
Rationale&amp;nbsp;¶ In this project, I analyzed communication patterns between OpenStreetMap (OSM) contributors relating to their mapping activities. Since 2014, contributors have had the ability to engage in public discussions directly related to a given OSM changeset.</description></item><item><title>Emotional Cartography: Mapping Feelings of Anxiety in London</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/emotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/emotion/</guid><description>Only when emotions, feelings, values, and ethics as well as a commitment to social justice become integral elements of our geospatial practices will moral geospatial practices become possible. Only then can GT help create a less violent and more just world. 1
Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ Our experience of inhabiting space in cities is unique and subjective. The meaning, memories, and emotions that we attach to our surroundings impact the ways that we engage and interact with them.</description></item><item><title>Event Detection through a Spatiotemporal Analysis of Geotagged Tweets</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/spatio-temporal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/spatio-temporal/</guid><description>Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ In this project, I was interested in exploring the spatial and temporal characteristics of tweets in London over a week-long time period. I analyzed the clustering patterns of approximately 40,000 tweets in both space and time. I found many clusters that could be linked to specific events taking place in the city. For example, I was able to detect events such as a West Ham vs Watford football game and an Adam Lambert concert.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Montreal's Legibility using Google Street View</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/legibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/legibility/</guid><description>This project was an investigation into the ways that we perceive and understand the urban landscapes around us.
Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ In his seminal book, The Image of the City, Kevin Lynch identified legibility as an important characteristic of pleasurable and engaging cities1. Legibility is the perceptual quality of urban landscapes that makes them remarkable and distinctive. A city made up of highly legible environments will be clearly imagined in the minds of those that live within it.</description></item><item><title>hi, i'm hannah</title><link>https://hannahker.com/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/about/</guid><description>I am interested in exploring the ways that (geospatial) data can contribute to making cities, towns, and communities more equitable and sustainable. I am particularly fascinated by the applications of non-traditional data sources, such as those from crowdsourcing projects or social media platforms.
Currently&amp;nbsp;¶ I am working as a Humanitarian Data Scientist at MapAction. In this role, I am contributing to efforts to improve information management during humanitarian crises. Within the Predictive Analytics Team at the UN OCHA&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Humanitarian Data, I am also working to create and validate predictive models that can enable early response to crises.</description></item><item><title>Cultural Landscapes and Montreal's Orange Julep Restaurant</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/oj/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/oj/</guid><description>Landscape allows and even encourages us to dream. 1
This quote from the renowned geographer, Yi-Fu Tuan, provides a useful starting point from which to examine the significance of the Orange Julep. While the Orange Julep is a unique building in the midst of a bland urban highway landscape, its existence is so much more than what meets the eye. The fantasy and imagination surrounding the Julep is what gives this Montreal landmark its true significance.</description></item></channel></rss>