<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Hannah Ker</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Hannah Ker</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:21:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hannahker.com/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using SVR to predict travel times in London</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/traffic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/traffic/</guid><description>Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ Using data collected from London&amp;rsquo;s ANPR camera system, I built and trained a machine learning model to predict travel times across 22 road links in central London.
The data&amp;nbsp;¶ This data was collected as part of the London Congestion Analysis Project and provides travel times (in sec/meter), aggregated at 5 min intervals for road links throughout London. This data was collected between January 1st, 2011 and January 30th, 2011 and includes observations between 6am-9pm for each day.</description></item><item><title>Using NLP to analyze OpenStreetMap changeset discussions</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/discussions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/discussions/</guid><description>Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ I used topic modelling and sentiment analysis to computationally investigate OpenStreetMap (OSM) changeset discussions. Specifically, I explored the following research question: What is the subject and tone of OSM changeset discussions between contributors in the United States over the past 90 days?
Rationale&amp;nbsp;¶ In this project, I analyzed communication patterns between OpenStreetMap (OSM) contributors relating to their mapping activities. Since 2014, contributors have had the ability to engage in public discussions directly related to a given OSM changeset.</description></item><item><title>Emotional Cartography: Mapping Feelings of Anxiety in London</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/emotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/emotion/</guid><description>Only when emotions, feelings, values, and ethics as well as a commitment to social justice become integral elements of our geospatial practices will moral geospatial practices become possible. Only then can GT help create a less violent and more just world. 1
Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ Our experience of inhabiting space in cities is unique and subjective. The meaning, memories, and emotions that we attach to our surroundings impact the ways that we engage and interact with them.</description></item><item><title>Event Detection through a Spatiotemporal Analysis of Geotagged Tweets</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/spatio-temporal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/spatio-temporal/</guid><description>Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ In this project, I was interested in exploring the spatial and temporal characteristics of tweets in London over a week-long time period. I analyzed the clustering patterns of approximately 40,000 tweets in both space and time. I found many clusters that could be linked to specific events taking place in the city. For example, I was able to detect events such as a West Ham vs Watford football game and an Adam Lambert concert.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Montreal's Legibility using Google Street View</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/legibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/legibility/</guid><description>This project was an investigation into the ways that we perceive and understand the urban landscapes around us.
Overview&amp;nbsp;¶ In his seminal book, The Image of the City, Kevin Lynch identified legibility as an important characteristic of pleasurable and engaging cities1. Legibility is the perceptual quality of urban landscapes that makes them remarkable and distinctive. A city made up of highly legible environments will be clearly imagined in the minds of those that live within it.</description></item><item><title>Cultural Landscapes and Montreal's Orange Julep Restaurant</title><link>https://hannahker.com/research/oj/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 12:41:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hannahker.com/research/oj/</guid><description>Landscape allows and even encourages us to dream. 1
This quote from the renowned geographer, Yi-Fu Tuan, provides a useful starting point from which to examine the significance of the Orange Julep. While the Orange Julep is a unique building in the midst of a bland urban highway landscape, its existence is so much more than what meets the eye. The fantasy and imagination surrounding the Julep is what gives this Montreal landmark its true significance.</description></item></channel></rss>